October 7 is important for what it was,
an important operation of the Palestinian
resistance.
It is important because on that day tens
of thousands of people
imprisoned for decades in a concentration
camp, in an open-air prison,
tore down walls, tore down fences.
In all acts of resistance, in all acts of
war carried out by human beings,
there may have been some marginal episodes
that were wrong,
but we can compare October 7 to one of the
most important partisan actions,
for example of the Italian Resistance,
like the one in Via Rasella,
in which, as we know, there were civilian
deaths, even a child.
But this, even our regret over it, if you
like,
cannot change the perspective from which
we analyse that event.
That is an act of resistance.